[
    {
        "question": "Which recently appointed Woman Chief Minister is also India's 18th Woman Chief Minister?",
        "options": [
            "Shikha Roy  ",
            "Rekha Gupta ",
            "Poonam Sharma ",
            "Neelam Pahelwan  "
        ],
        "answer": "Rekha Gupta ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the 26th Chief Election Commissioner of India?",
        "options": [
            "Sunil Arora ",
            "Sushil Chandra ",
            "Rajiv Kumar ",
            "Gyanesh Kumar "
        ],
        "answer": "Gyanesh Kumar ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the new Election Commissioner of the Election Commission of India in February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Achal Kumar Jyoti ",
            "Om Prakash Rawat ",
            "V. S. Sampath ",
            "Vivek Joshi "
        ],
        "answer": "Vivek Joshi ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the term of the Chief Election Commissioner and the Commissioner of the Election Commission of India?",
        "options": [
            "six years or 65 years, whichever is earlier ",
            "six years or 62 years, whichever is earlier ",
            "six years or 60 years, whichever is earlier ",
            "six years or 65 years, whichever is earlier "
        ],
        "answer": "six years or 65 years, whichever is earlier ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "India\u2019s first Open Air Art Wall Museum has been inaugurated in which city?",
        "options": [
            "Chennai  ",
            "Hyderabad  ",
            "Bengaluru  ",
            "New Delhi "
        ],
        "answer": "New Delhi ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the first General Assembly meeting of the Inter-governmental oragnisation,the International Organization for Marine Aids to Navigation (IAL",
        "options": [
            "held? ",
            "Singapore ",
            "Malaysia  ",
            "Indonesia  ",
            "Japan "
        ],
        "answer": "held? ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the major festival of the Missing tribe, recently in the news?",
        "options": [
            "Bihu ",
            "Hornbill ",
            "Ali Ai Ligang ",
            "Losar "
        ],
        "answer": "Ali Ai Ligang ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company secured a 10 GWh battery capacity under India's PLI ACC Scheme for Advanced Chemistry Cells?",
        "options": [
            "Reliance industries  ",
            "Tata Group  ",
            "Adani Group  ",
            "Mahindra and Mahindra "
        ],
        "answer": "Reliance industries  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state in India has expanded its Soil Health Card Yojana to promote sustainable farming?",
        "options": [
            "Maharashtra ",
            "Tamil Nadu ",
            "Gujarat ",
            "Uttar Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Gujarat ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company ranked 2nd globally in the FutureBrand Index 2024, surpassing Apple?",
        "options": [
            "Microsoft ",
            "Reliance industries  ",
            "Samsung ",
            "Netflix "
        ],
        "answer": "Reliance industries  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company launched the AI-powered customer support platform 'Nugget'?",
        "options": [
            "Blinkit ",
            "Hyperpure ",
            "Zomato ",
            "Swiggy "
        ],
        "answer": "Zomato ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state is launching India\u2019s first government-led initiative for the safe collection and disposal of expired medicines?",
        "options": [
            "Tamil Nadu ",
            "Karnataka ",
            "Maharashtra ",
            "Kerala "
        ],
        "answer": "Kerala ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country was declared free of the gambiense form of human African trypanosomiasis (HAT) by the WHO on January 29, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Senegal ",
            "Guinea ",
            "Mali ",
            "Liberia "
        ],
        "answer": "Guinea ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is involved in a strategic partnership with India, focusing on trade, energy, and tax cooperation?",
        "options": [
            "Qatar ",
            "Saudi Arabia ",
            "United Arab Emirates ",
            "Kuwait "
        ],
        "answer": "Qatar ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company projected the 8th Missile Cum Ammunition Barge, LSAM 11?",
        "options": [
            "SECON Engineering ",
            "L&T Shipbuilding ",
            "Mazagon Dock Limited ",
            "Cochin Shipyard "
        ],
        "answer": "SECON Engineering ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state assembly became the first in India to install a translator facility for multiple regional languages?",
        "options": [
            "Bihar ",
            "Uttar Pradesh ",
            "Madhya Pradesh ",
            "Uttarakhand "
        ],
        "answer": "Uttar Pradesh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state approved key schemes for women, youth, and development, including revamping the Dulari Kanya Scheme?",
        "options": [
            "Assam ",
            "Meghalaya ",
            "Arunachal Pradesh ",
            "Nagaland "
        ],
        "answer": "Arunachal Pradesh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has recently joined OPEC+?",
        "options": [
            "Iran ",
            "Qatar ",
            "Brazil ",
            "Argentina "
        ],
        "answer": "Brazil ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has recently been appointed as the Deputy Secretary in the Department of Expenditure?",
        "options": [
            "Raghav Chadha ",
            "Sukhbir Singh Sandhu ",
            "Vivek Arora ",
            "Mritunjay Shrikanthan "
        ],
        "answer": "Mritunjay Shrikanthan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who set up the Dinesh Khara Committee, recently seen in the news?",
        "options": [
            "Reserve Bank of India (RBI) ",
            "Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority (IRDAI) ",
            "Securities and Exchange Board of India (SEBI) ",
            "None of the above.  "
        ],
        "answer": "Insurance Regulatory and Development Authority (IRDAI) ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which among the following best describes Majorana 1, recently seen in the news?",
        "options": [
            "A newly discovered subatomic particle. ",
            "A new spacecraft designed for Mars exploration. ",
            "A quantum computing chip. ",
            "A propulsion technology developed for faster space travel "
        ],
        "answer": "A quantum computing chip. ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bima -Application Supported by Blocked Amount (ASB",
        "options": [
            "was in news recently, it was introduced ",
            "RBI ",
            "SEBI ",
            "NPCI ",
            "IRDAI "
        ],
        "answer": "NPCI ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Centre has extended the tenure of NITI Aayog Chief Executive Officer (CEO) B V R Subrahmanyam by how many years?",
        "options": [
            "one year  ",
            "two years  ",
            "three years  ",
            "four years "
        ],
        "answer": "one year  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The government of India has extended the term of Chief Economic Advisor to the Ministry of Finance,V Anantha Nageswaran by how many years?",
        "options": [
            "Two years ",
            "Three years  ",
            "Four years  ",
            "Five years "
        ],
        "answer": "Two years ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian women have been included in the Times Magazine's \u201c Women of the Year\u201d 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Gita Gopinath ",
            "Roshni Nadar Malhotra ",
            "Purnima Devi Barman ",
            "Kiran Mazumdar-Shaw "
        ],
        "answer": "Purnima Devi Barman ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many women have been included in the Times Magazine's \u201c Women of the Year\u201d 2025?",
        "options": [
            "10 ",
            "12 ",
            "16 ",
            "13 "
        ],
        "answer": "13 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who inaugurated the first edition of the SOUL Leadership Conclave 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Draupadi Murmu  ",
            "Narendra Modi  ",
            "Amit Shah  ",
            "Rajnath Singh "
        ],
        "answer": "Narendra Modi  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the second country in the world to introduce an Electronic Personnel License (EPL) for pilots in the civil aviation sector?",
        "options": [
            "Japan  ",
            "Russia  ",
            "India ",
            "China "
        ],
        "answer": "India ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Financial Services Institutions Bureau (FSIB) has recommended Dinesh Pant and Ratnakar Patnaik for the positions of Managing Directors (MDs) of which organisation?",
        "options": [
            "has recommended Dinesh Pant and Ratnakar Patnaik ",
            "Life Insurance Corporation of India (LIC) ",
            "Steel Authority of India Limited (SAIL) ",
            "Garden Reach Shipbuilders & Engineers (GRSE) ",
            "Food Safety and Standards Authority of India (FSSAI) "
        ],
        "answer": "has recommended Dinesh Pant and Ratnakar Patnaik ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding Digital Brand Identity Manual:  1. It aims to establish a standardized and cohesive digital identity across all government ministries and platforms.  2. It focuses on simplifying and standardizing government websites so that citizens from diverse backgrounds can easily navigate.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Mising people are one of the largest tribal groups in which Indian state?",
        "options": [
            "Odisha ",
            "Assam ",
            "West Bengal ",
            "Manipur "
        ],
        "answer": "Assam ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Vertical Propellant Mixer:  1. It is the largest solid propellant mixing equipment globally.  2. It is developed and designed by Satish Dhawan Space Centre in collaboration with Central Manufacturing Technology Institute.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the OPEC+ :  1. It is a group of 22 oil-exporting countries aim to work together on adjusting crude oil production to bring stability to the oil market.  2. It only consists of nations from African continent as its members.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "1 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the new MD & CEO of SBI Cards?",
        "options": [
            "Abhijit Chakravorty ",
            "Rajeev Kumar ",
            "Salila Pande ",
            "Amit Sharma "
        ],
        "answer": "Salila Pande ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What percentage stake will 360 ONE Asset acquire in Bharti AXA Life Insurance?",
        "options": [
            "10% ",
            "5% ",
            "20% ",
            "15% "
        ],
        "answer": "15% ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city is Google's largest campus in India, Ananta, located?",
        "options": [
            "Mumbai ",
            "Bengaluru ",
            "Hyderabad ",
            "Gurugram "
        ],
        "answer": "Bengaluru ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization developed the world\u2019s largest propellant mixer?",
        "options": [
            "NASA ",
            "SpaceX ",
            "ISRO ",
            "Roscosmos "
        ],
        "answer": "ISRO ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]